You're either S.W.A.T. or you're not.
S.W.A.T. is a action, thriller, crime film directed by Clark Johnson.
Hondo Harrelson recruits Jim Street to join an elite
unit of the Los Angeles Police Department.
Together they seek out more members, including tough
Deke Kay and single mom Chris Sanchez.
The team's first big assignment is to escort crime boss Alex Montel to prison.
It seems routine, but when Montel offers a huge reward to anyone who can break
him free, criminals of various stripes step up for the prize.
Sgt. Dan 'Hondo' Harrelson, played by Samuel L. Jackson.
Jim Street, played by Colin Farrell.
Chris Sanchez, played by Michelle Rodriguez.
Deacon 'Deke' Kaye, played by LL Cool J.
T.J. McCabe, played by Josh Charles.
Brian Gamble, played by Jeremy Renner.
is a 2003 American action crime thriller film based on the
1975–76 television series of the same name.
The film was directed by Clark Johnson from a screenplay by David Ayer and
David McKenna, based on a story by Ron Mita and Jim McClain.
It stars Samuel L.
Jackson, Colin Farrell, Michelle Rodriguez, LL Cool J, Josh Charles,
Jeremy Renner, Brian Van Holt and Olivier Martinez with Reg E.
Cathey and Larry Poindexter in supporting roles.
Like the TV series, the film revolves around a police Special Weapons and
Tactics (SWAT) team operating in Los Angeles California.
The plot follows Hondo (Jackson) and his SWAT team as they are tasked to escort an imprisoned drug kingpin/international
fugitive to prison after he offers a $100 million reward to anyone who can break him out of police custody.
Plans for a film adaptation of the 1975 TV series began in the
1990s, but never materialized until the early 2000s.
Johnson was hired as director and Jackson, Farrell
and LL Cool J were cast in 2002.
was released in the United States on August 8, 2003, by Sony Pictures Releasing.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $207.7 million
worldwide against a production budget of $70 million.
A direct-to-video sequel, S.W.A.T.: Firefight, was released in 2011.
The film explores themes of liberation, transport of
prisoners, special unit, los angeles, california.
The tone is intense.